<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Herreid on Sam Herreid</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sam Herreid on Sam Herreid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 All photos and figures by Sam Herreid (profile photo by M. Schlapfer, glacier bike thumbnail by S. Bridwell)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Denali (6,194 m) so big? Caught inside the tectonic wake of a migrating restraining bend</title>
      <link>/publication/denali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/denali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topography along strike-slip fault restraining bends is theoretically self-limited by erosion, block translation and the expected abandonment of fault bends. However, Denali (6,194 m) and Foraker (5,304 m) are located within a restraining bend of the dextral Denali Fault system. We reveal the role of bend evolution in mountain building with physical experiments scaled to simulate the Alaska Mount McKinley restraining bend (MMRB). Despite the natural complexity of the MMRB, first-order patterns (of strike-slip separation rates, uplift and lateral bend migration) from the geologic data align with patterns from scaled experiments. Thermochronology, seismicity, and slip rate data show that the persistence of a single Denali Fault strand through the ~6 Ma MMRB is facilitated by simultaneous advection of crust through the bend and migration of the eastern vertex of the bend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can thermal imagery tell us about glacier melt below rock debris?</title>
      <link>/publication/thermal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/thermal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CW9SAC-llbg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;5 post series&lt;/a&gt; on my Instagram gives a summary of this paper in accessable language and tells the story about what it took to personally finance it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Below] Oblique image of Canwell Glacier from the same helicopter flight used to capture the (straight downward-looking) images above (July 29th, 2016 11:00 AM local Alaska time).
&lt;img src=&#34;canObli.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2000&#34; height=&#34;2000&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock debris on the surface of a glacier can dramatically reduce the local melt rate, where the primary factor governing melt reduction is debris layer thickness. Relating surface temperature to debris thickness is a recurring approach in the literature, yet demonstrations of reproducibility have been limited. Here, I present the results of a field experiment conducted on the Canwell Glacier, Alaska, United States to constrain how thermal data can be used in glaciology. These datasets include, 1) a measured sub-daily “Østrem curve” time-series; 2) a time-series of high resolution thermal images capturing several segments of different debris thicknesses including the measurements from 1); 3) a thermal profile through a 38 cm debris cover; and 4) two Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER) satellite thermal images acquired within 2 and 3 min of a field-based thermal camera image. I show that, while clear sky conditions are when space-borne thermal sensors can image a glacier, this is an unfavorable time, limiting the likelihood that different thicknesses of debris will have a unique thermal signature. I then propose an empirical approach to estimate debris thickness and compare it to two recently published methods. I demonstrate that instantaneous calibration is essential in the previously published methods, where model parameters calibrated only 1 h prior to a repeat thermal image return diminished debris thickness estimates, while the method proposed here remains robust through time and does not appear to require re-calibration. I then propose a method that uses a time-series of surface temperature at one location and debris thickness to estimate bare-ice and sub-debris melt. Results show comparable cumulative melt estimates to a recently published method that requires an explicit/external estimate of bare ice melt. Finally, I show that sub-pixel corrections to ASTER thermal imagery can enable a close resemblance to high resolution, field-based thermal imagery. These results offer a deeper insight into what thermal data can and cannot tell us about surface debris properties and glacier melt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can thermal imagery tell us about glacier melt below rock debris?</title>
      <link>/publication/thermal_featured/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/thermal_featured/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CW9SAC-llbg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;5 post series&lt;/a&gt; on my Instagram gives a summary of this paper in accessable language and tells the story about what it took to personally finance it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Below] Oblique image of Canwell Glacier from the same helicopter flight used to capture the (straight downward-looking) images above (July 29th, 2016 11:00 AM local Alaska time).
&lt;img src=&#34;canObli.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2000&#34; height=&#34;2000&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock debris on the surface of a glacier can dramatically reduce the local melt rate, where the primary factor governing melt reduction is debris layer thickness. Relating surface temperature to debris thickness is a recurring approach in the literature, yet demonstrations of reproducibility have been limited. Here, I present the results of a field experiment conducted on the Canwell Glacier, Alaska, United States to constrain how thermal data can be used in glaciology. These datasets include, 1) a measured sub-daily “Østrem curve” time-series; 2) a time-series of high resolution thermal images capturing several segments of different debris thicknesses including the measurements from 1); 3) a thermal profile through a 38 cm debris cover; and 4) two Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER) satellite thermal images acquired within 2 and 3 min of a field-based thermal camera image. I show that, while clear sky conditions are when space-borne thermal sensors can image a glacier, this is an unfavorable time, limiting the likelihood that different thicknesses of debris will have a unique thermal signature. I then propose an empirical approach to estimate debris thickness and compare it to two recently published methods. I demonstrate that instantaneous calibration is essential in the previously published methods, where model parameters calibrated only 1 h prior to a repeat thermal image return diminished debris thickness estimates, while the method proposed here remains robust through time and does not appear to require re-calibration. I then propose a method that uses a time-series of surface temperature at one location and debris thickness to estimate bare-ice and sub-debris melt. Results show comparable cumulative melt estimates to a recently published method that requires an explicit/external estimate of bare ice melt. Finally, I show that sub-pixel corrections to ASTER thermal imagery can enable a close resemblance to high resolution, field-based thermal imagery. These results offer a deeper insight into what thermal data can and cannot tell us about surface debris properties and glacier melt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing the Arctic (Book Chapter)</title>
      <link>/publication/arcticocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/arcticocean/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of rock debris covering Earth&#39;s glaciers</title>
      <link>/publication/global/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/global/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A summary of this paper written in accessable language for the Nature Sustainability Community &amp;ldquo;Behind the Paper&amp;rdquo; series is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://sustainabilitycommunity.springernature.com/posts/rocks-catching-a-ride-out-of-the-mountains-on-a-glacier-might-be-keeping-sea-level-rise-a-little-lower-than-expected&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock debris can accumulate on glacier surfaces and dramatically reduce glacier melt. The structure of a debris cover is unique to each glacier and sensitive to climate. Despite this, debris cover has been omitted from global glacier models and forecasts of their response to a changing climate. Fundamental to resolving these omissions is a global map of debris cover and an estimate of its future spatial evolution. Here we use Landsat imagery and a detailed correction to the Randolph Glacier Inventory to show that 7.3% of mountain glacier area is debris-covered and over half of Earth’s debris is concentrated in three regions: Alaska (38.6% of total debris-covered area), Southwest Asia (12.6%) and Greenland (12.0%). We use a set of new metrics including stage, the current position of a glacier on its trajectory towards reaching its spatial debris cover carrying capacity, to quantify the state of glaciers. Debris cover is present on 44% of Earth’s glaciers and prominent (&amp;gt;1.0 km2) on 15%. 20% of Earth’s glaciers have a substantial percentage of debris cover for which net stage is 36% and the bulk of individual glaciers have evolved beyond an optimal moraine configuration favorable for debris cover expansion. Use of this dataset in global scale models will enable improved estimates of melt over 10.6% of the global glacier domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;website_global.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2000&#34; height=&#34;2000&#34; /&gt;
The state and evolution trajectory of Earth&amp;rsquo;s glaciers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of rock debris covering Earth&#39;s glaciers</title>
      <link>/publication/global_featured/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/global_featured/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A summary of this paper written in accessable language for the Nature Sustainability Community &amp;ldquo;Behind the Paper&amp;rdquo; series is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://sustainabilitycommunity.springernature.com/posts/rocks-catching-a-ride-out-of-the-mountains-on-a-glacier-might-be-keeping-sea-level-rise-a-little-lower-than-expected&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rock debris can accumulate on glacier surfaces and dramatically reduce glacier melt. The structure of a debris cover is unique to each glacier and sensitive to climate. Despite this, debris cover has been omitted from global glacier models and forecasts of their response to a changing climate. Fundamental to resolving these omissions is a global map of debris cover and an estimate of its future spatial evolution. Here we use Landsat imagery and a detailed correction to the Randolph Glacier Inventory to show that 7.3% of mountain glacier area is debris-covered and over half of Earth’s debris is concentrated in three regions: Alaska (38.6% of total debris-covered area), Southwest Asia (12.6%) and Greenland (12.0%). We use a set of new metrics including stage, the current position of a glacier on its trajectory towards reaching its spatial debris cover carrying capacity, to quantify the state of glaciers. Debris cover is present on 44% of Earth’s glaciers and prominent (&amp;gt;1.0 km2) on 15%. 20% of Earth’s glaciers have a substantial percentage of debris cover for which net stage is 36% and the bulk of individual glaciers have evolved beyond an optimal moraine configuration favorable for debris cover expansion. Use of this dataset in global scale models will enable improved estimates of melt over 10.6% of the global glacier domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;website_global.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2000&#34; height=&#34;2000&#34; /&gt;
The state and evolution trajectory of Earth&amp;rsquo;s glaciers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated detection of ice cliffs within supraglacial debris cover</title>
      <link>/icecliffs_featured_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/icecliffs_featured_old/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ice cliffs within a supraglacial debris cover have been identified as a source for high ablation relative to the surrounding debris-covered area. Due to their small relative size and steep orientation, ice cliffs are difficult to detect using nadir-looking space borne sensors. The method presented here uses surface slopes calculated from digital elevation model (DEM) data to map ice cliff geometry and produce an ice cliff probability map. Surface slope thresholds, which can be sensitive to geographic location and/or data quality, are selected automatically. The method also attempts to include area at the (often narrowing) ends of ice cliffs which could otherwise be neglected due to signal saturation in surface slope data. The method was calibrated in the Eastern Alaska Range, Alaska, USA, against a control ice cliff dataset derived from high resolution visible and thermal data. Using the same input parameter set that performed best in Alaska, the method was tested against ice cliffs manually mapped in the Khumbu Himal, Nepal. Our results suggest the method can accommodate different glaciological settings and different DEM data sources without a data intensive (high resolution, multi-data source) re-calibration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated detection of ice cliffs within supraglacial debris cover</title>
      <link>/publication/icecliffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/icecliffs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ice cliffs within a supraglacial debris cover have been identified as a source for high ablation relative to the surrounding debris-covered area. Due to their small relative size and steep orientation, ice cliffs are difficult to detect using nadir-looking space borne sensors. The method presented here uses surface slopes calculated from digital elevation model (DEM) data to map ice cliff geometry and produce an ice cliff probability map. Surface slope thresholds, which can be sensitive to geographic location and/or data quality, are selected automatically. The method also attempts to include area at the (often narrowing) ends of ice cliffs which could otherwise be neglected due to signal saturation in surface slope data. The method was calibrated in the Eastern Alaska Range, Alaska, USA, against a control ice cliff dataset derived from high resolution visible and thermal data. Using the same input parameter set that performed best in Alaska, the method was tested against ice cliffs manually mapped in the Khumbu Himal, Nepal. Our results suggest the method can accommodate different glaciological settings and different DEM data sources without a data intensive (high resolution, multi-data source) re-calibration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A globally complete map of supraglacial debris cover and a new toolkit for debris cover research</title>
      <link>/talk/polarcopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/polarcopy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A growing canon of literature is focused on resolving the processes and implications of debris cover on glaciers.
However, this work is often confined to a handful of glaciers that were likely selected based on criteria optimizing
their suitability to test a specific hypothesis or logistical ease. The role of debris cover in a glacier system is likely
to not go overlooked in forthcoming research, yet the magnitude of this role at a global scale has not yet been fully
described. Here, we present a map of debris cover for all glacierized regions on Earth including the Greenland
Ice Sheet using 30 m Landsat data. This dataset will begin to open a wider context to the high quality, localized
findings from the debris-covered glacier research community and help inform large-scale modeling efforts. A
global map of debris cover also facilitates analysis attempting to isolate first order geomorphological and climate
controls of supraglacial debris production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthering the objective of expanding the inclusion of debris cover in forthcoming research, we also present an
under development suite of open-source, Python based tools. Requiring minimal and often freely available input
data, we have automated the mapping of: i) debris cover, ii) ice cliffs, iii) debris cover evolution over the Landsat
era and iv) glacier flow instabilities from altered debris structures. At the present time, debris extent is the only
globally complete quantity but with the expanding repository of high quality global datasets and further tool
development minimizing manual tasks and computational cost, we foresee all of these tools being applied globally
in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-lapse thermal imagery used to resolve sub-debris glacier melt in Alaska</title>
      <link>/talk/polar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/polar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canwell Glacier Research Program</title>
      <link>/project/canwellglacier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/canwellglacier/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;During my undergraduate at the University of Alaska Fairbanks, I participated in a summer Field Glaciology course. While we focused on traditional bare-ice glaciological methods, I was fixated on how the measurements we were making were not representative of the neighboring ice covered by rocks. When I learned that that debris-covered portions of glaciers were often treated like bare glacier ice in most studies, I wrote a student research proposal to investigate this on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the infancy of the program, supplies and trips relied on self-funding, I was loaned expensive sensors by professors who didn&amp;rsquo;t have any real reason to trust me (notably &lt;a href=&#34;http://apl.uw.edu/people/profile.php?last_name=Arendt&amp;amp;first_name=Anthony&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Anthony Arendt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://gps.alaska.edu/jeff/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jeff Freymueller&lt;/a&gt;), science gear was ferried to the glacier by bicycle, many trips were done solo and a lot of challenges were met, like the classic failed steam drilling attempt through debris-covered ice. Applying for and receiving several competitive student grants allowed me to purchase a &lt;a href=&#34;https://kovacsicedrillingequipment.com/mechanical-drilling/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kovacs ice drill&lt;/a&gt;, charter Super Cubs and &lt;a href=&#34;https://aklandex.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;helicopters&lt;/a&gt;, purchase sensors and build two weather stations from scratch. I have learned a lot since 2011 and have managed to keep a steady flow of data on a near annual basis with each successive field campaign expanding in scope. The first publication to use Canwell Glacier data was published in May 2018 and several more, digging deeper into the data archive, are in preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;press&#34;&gt;Press&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adn.com/alaska-news/science/2016/09/17/meet-the-man-studying-alaskas-glaciers-by-living-on-one-for-a-few-days-at-a-time-each-summer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2016 Anchorage Daily News article by Ned Rozell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://uaf.edu/ursa/spotlight/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2014 poster presentation to members of the US Congress in Washington DC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;past-funding&#34;&gt;Past funding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016: Northumbria University PhD fieldwork funding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2013 - 2014: Undergraduate Research &amp;amp; Scholarly Activity (URSA) research grant. &amp;ldquo;Developing a multi-method approach to improve regional-scale glacier melt estimates by considering debris cover&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2012: University of Alaska Fairbanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uaf.edu/uafgov/files/staff-council/meetings/fy12/sc227/Attachment_227_2_TAB_Committee_Report_April_2012.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Technology Advisory Board (TAB)&lt;/a&gt;  equipment grant. “Thermal camera for student use.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2011 - 2012: University of Alaska Fairbanks Undergraduate Research &amp;amp; Scholarly Activity (URSA) research grant. &amp;ldquo;Differential melt of debris-covered glaciers in the Alaska Range.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2010 - 2012: University of Alaska Fairbanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cgc.uaf.edu/student_grant/awardees-2010.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Global Change&lt;/a&gt; research grant. &amp;ldquo;Effects of debris cover on glaciers in Alaska&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debris Cover Tools</title>
      <link>/project/dct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glaciers are constantly in a state of flux. In addition to glacier evolution, rock debris rafting on the surface, surface streams and supraglacial lakes are all also evolving, likely at independent rates. The glacier surge event shown above is an extreme example of this, but within an unstable climate, all glaciers will undergo dramatic changes over decadal to centennial time-scales. Quantifying this change is the first step in understanding and modeling the greater questions in glaciology. The front edge of this effort is currently centered around large-scale to global mapping products optimized for accuracy, consistency and computational efficiency. To contribute to this effort, my co-authors and I have written two &amp;ldquo;Automated detection of&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; articles aimed at subdividing &lt;em&gt;glacier area&lt;/em&gt; into very specific categories that will increase the ability of computer models to approach what is truly found in nature and make future projections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samherreid/DebrisCoverTools&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Version 1 of Debris Cover Tools&lt;/a&gt; was released in May 2018 and includes a new method for mapping ice cliffs. There are several more tools in preparation and improvements to Version 1. Currently, the code calls functions within ArcPy that require an &amp;lsquo;Advanced&amp;rsquo; ArcGIS license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global scale analyses and products</title>
      <link>/project/global/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/global/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to derive a global debris cover map at an operative quality, the Randolph Glacier Inventory Version 6.0 needed to be corrected and updated. Because I was the sole glaciologist to manually correct this dataset, there is now a heightened level of consistency that has never before been present in a global glacier dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a high confidence map of glacier area and debris cover, an equilibrium line estimate can be made for glaciers with sufficient debris cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the derivation of each galcier&amp;rsquo;s equilibrium line, the accumulation area ratio (AAR), a metrics of glacier health, can be calculated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here I was able to diverge from the common, and not-so-informative, metric &amp;ldquo; percent debris-covered&amp;rdquo;  to define four new metrics, that, together, describe the state and geometric configuration of each glacier&amp;rsquo;s debris cover. These new metrics are defined below with examples from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fig3-01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2000&#34; height=&#34;2000&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The updated RGI, debris maps and per-glacier metric values are all available for all glacierized regions on Earth &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3866466&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landslides on glaciers</title>
      <link>/project/landslides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/landslides/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Landslides, more technically rock avalanches, are striking features when deposited onto glaciers. Since 2010 I have been both scientifically and personally interested in visiting as many as I can while also keeping an eye on satellite imagery for the next big one&amp;hellip; They are all quite unique, as you will see from some of my favorites shown below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide1.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Delta Mountains, a sub-range of the Alaska Range. Landslides are shown in red and letters correspond to the locations of the images below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide2.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hayes Range, a sub-range of the Alaska Range. Landslides are shown in red and letters correspond to the locations of the images below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide3.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; In 2010, Andy Sterns and I camped for two weeks on the West Fork Robertson Glacier. Our tent was on the medial moraine just below the arrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide4.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; When we returned to the same spot in 2011 a fresh landslide had been deposited almost exactly where our camp was the previous year. The arrows point to the same location in both images. Notice how the debris &amp;ldquo;jumped&amp;rdquo; over the medial moraine! Glaciers, and the rock debris on top of them, are in constant state of flux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide5.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Investigating the debris from the landslide shown above. Andy Sterns for scale. Notice the rock size and size distribution: small and uniform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide6.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; In contrast to the image above. Investigating landslide debris on the West Fork Glacier (Hayes Range). Andy Sterns for scale, standing on a house sized rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide7.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; West Fork Roberson Glacier, landslide deposition ~1981. Notice the ridge along the perimeter of the landslide, this is common but not always present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide8.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d)&lt;/strong&gt; Downward-looking thermal image captured during a flight with &lt;a href=&#34;http://glacieradventures.blogspot.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Martin Truffer&lt;/a&gt; over Black Rapids Glacier. Several landslides on Black Rapids Glacier, along with many others all arcoss the Alaska Range, were deposited during the 2002 Denali Fault earthquake. Notice the shading effect on surface temperature from the giant boulders and the &amp;ldquo;cold&amp;rdquo; spots on the meters thick debris cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Slide9.JPG&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(e)&lt;/strong&gt; One of the several landslides deposited onto Gakona Glacier in 2002. Maybe it goes without saying, but the winter biking here turns out to be awful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal imagery in glaciology</title>
      <link>/project/thermal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/thermal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The thumbnail image to this project is of fist to silt-sized clasts on an otherwise bare glacier ice surface. The thumbnail image falls within one or two pixels in the image above which is looking straight down from a helicopter with an image width of several hundred meters. High resolution thermal data holds many answers about debris cover but has received limited attention from glaciologists. Work that is in preparation will detail new methods for acquisition, processing and applications for glaciologists. Coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
