<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Sam Herreid</title>
    <link>https://samherreid.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://samherreid.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://samherreid.io/media/icon_hu4111fabdab116352ce8a62ad911042e7_28769_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to The Past</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/freetrail_wau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/freetrail_wau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Excerpt from the full article published on  &lt;a href=&#34;https://freetrail.com/a-letter-to-the-past/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Freetrail.com&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/reel/CowcxkvgIGp/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt; showing Antarctic trail running in year 2523.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my fellow collegiate runners in 2025,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people think the moment in time they occupy is a pinnacle of historic importance. Usually it is not. But with the advantage of hindsight, I can confidently say you are alive during a pivotal era. The technological revolution you are bridging puts you in a unique situation, living a blend of primitive humanity and normal modern life. You’re living the last few decades where natural atmosphere cities cover all of planet Earth and C02 concentrations were a nominal 425 ppm. It’s also the last period before the blatantly precarious economic model of perpetual growth collapses leading, eventually, to Modern Economics and the EMMF (Earth Moon Mars Franc, we pronounce it “Em-eff”) following the NE (Near Extinction, we say “Nee”). The generations after you face the climate refugee crisis, The Yellowstone Eruption, the simultaneous bankruptcy of every country on the planet (so many countries!) and two world wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full aticle &lt;a href=&#34;https://freetrail.com/a-letter-to-the-past/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on Freetrail.com&lt;/a&gt;, and come back here to comment :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strava Hang Time Into the New Year</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/freetrail_strava/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/freetrail_strava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Excerpt from the full article published on  &lt;a href=&#34;https://freetrail.com/strava-hang-time-into-the-new-year/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Freetrail.com&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not obsessive over your training numbers, you’re either a recovered obsessor or you haven’t spent three paychecks on a sports watch yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I solved the classic 9.95-mile, run past my house to get a round number, fixation by splitting unit custody between my watch (imperial) and Strava (metric). Clean numbers on one device are a jumble on the other. This spun out my brain and it decided it no longer gave a shit. My legs, seeing exactly zero productive adaptation from +0.05 miles, co-signed dropping the absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I still scale my entire human worth on, however, is miles per week and, by extension, miles per year. I understand if you’re a real trail runner your primary metric is likely vertical gain, but if you’re a real trail runner, you don’t live in coastal New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have read about my urban ultras, a last ditch effort to maintain some semblance of adventure amid an otherwise unremarkable human experience by running routes better traversed by Greyhound buses. An edge case of this effort, a subset annual tradition of mine, draws on a fun, arbitrary choice made by some executive at Strava and implemented by some programmer with a line of code: the timestamp of an activity is pinned to its beginning, the moment you start your watch. (An activity’s end or middle point would also be perfectly acceptable conventions to define a single instance timestamp).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means a run of any duration, let’s say 10 hours, starting at 11:59 p.m. on December 31st, 2022 will be 10 hours of hang time running into 2023 that still gets counted, in Strava, towards 2022. The very last chance to touch up that year-end mileage sum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the rest of the aticle &lt;a href=&#34;https://freetrail.com/strava-hang-time-into-the-new-year/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on Freetrail.com&lt;/a&gt;, and come back here to leave a comment :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First blog post of all time!</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to samherreid.io! A new hub for my content spanning a handful of, not always complementary, fixations. My first personal website, samherreid.org, went live in June 2018 as a primarily academic website. It had some footnotes to my other interests, but was built specifically for the eyes of potential employers. I never said ‘‘fuck’’ on samherreid.org. But things are changing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the domain extension. No one has time to comment on things, those that do occupy a beautiful few percentages of our population. When samherreid.org launched there wasn’t public commenting, but a few people privately messaged me, laughing at my ambitious organization designation. It made some sense to me because it was a well-known extension and I’m not a commercial entity. But now that I am a co-founder of an actual nonprofit organization, I decided to switch my personal website to the trendy .io extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this website still has a comprehensive presentation of my science, I decided to ditch the selective resume format and host all of my creative fields in on one central &amp;ndash; and not social media &amp;ndash; location. Am I still applying for postdocs with a link to this website on my CV? Yes 😅, but I guess I’ve decided to be my whole self here, which means expect inline emojis and jokes about eating Tide Pods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new website has an uncomplicated comments section on all posts, articles and projects and I challenge you to be in the few percent who leave a comment, joke, question or criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Front Door to ____” Urban Ultra Series</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/freetrail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/freetrail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Excerpt from the full article published on  &lt;a href=&#34;https://freetrail.com/the-front-door-to-____-urban-ultra-series/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Freetrail.com&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My 20s were littered with Alaskan adventures. Things like 100+ mile off-trail multi-sport wilderness races, obscure marathons and ultras year round, bikepacking on glaciers and climbing frozen waterfalls. Growing up in Alaska’s interior is sort of like growing up ultra-Orthodox in Williamsburg, at some point during adolescence you start to comprehend that choices made by an earlier generation put your most crucial years of development in an all-immersive environment several deviations from the norm. Just like growing up in an insular Hasidic community, an Alaskan upbringing has its pros and cons. The obvious pros include a closeness to raw wilderness, big mountains, and unadulterated exploration. There are other pros too, like a deep sense of individuality and you can play the drums at 2 a.m. without upsetting your neighbors – because you don’t have any. The cons include grocery store produce so devoid of nutrients you’ll probably develop scurvy, being disconnected from everything that’s actually happening in the world, and air that assaults your skin 8 months out of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I left Alaska to get a PhD in Glaciology in northeast England, it was a rude awakening that: (1) social skills are key to human survival and (2) life outside of Alaska is absurdly mundane, to the point of attempting to eat a Tide Pod just so there’s something to talk about. I’m convinced that relentless political news cycles, televised sports, holiday traditions, and all other time-intensive mainstays of typical life are placeholders – filling time before the next Alaskan adventure. Unfortunately, most people, and now me as well, are likely going to be in this holding pattern for a lifetime. But this article isn’t a paid advertisement for the Alaska Tourism Bureau, it’s about how I’ve made life in the mundane work while keeping the detergent in the washing machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the rest of the aticle &lt;a href=&#34;https://freetrail.com/the-front-door-to-____-urban-ultra-series/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on Freetrail.com&lt;/a&gt;, and come back here to leave a comment :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Tamales are Good for the Planet, the Trail, and You</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/irunfar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/irunfar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Excerpt from the full article published on  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.irunfar.com/why-tamales-are-good-for-the-planet-the-trail-and-you&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;irunfar.com&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been annoyed by how many bars and gels I go through as an ultrarunner. Even though our sport leans hard toward environmental conscientiousness, I think we’re all pretty guilty of turning a blind eye to individual fuel packaging and the waste we are generating. We post pictures of the mountain of snacks we’ll consume during a race like a badge of honor. Just as a big game hunter might see pride in their kill photos, blind or indifferent to the harm, perhaps so are we to our environmental toll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, I sometimes bake potatoes, put them in a tortilla and call myself a hero, but if I’m honest, I’ve only done that a handful of times and when I’m five hours into a run, starch on starch pocket mush is just not as palatable as a Honey Stinger stroopwafel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if there was a food hack, one that has existed in many equatorial cultures for longer than I am willing to regurgitate to you from Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any proper online recipe, this is the part where I give you a 3,500-word personal history about the enticing smells that would waft out of my grandma’s kitchen and how I now use modern ingredients that just aren’t the same as hers. I would go on to tell you about the extensive trial and error it took to arrive at the recipe before you today, which is suspiciously identical to that which is found in the Joy of Cooking, but don’t focus on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, there’s no backstory and we both have short attention spans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s tamales. This article is about tamales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the rest of the aticle &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.irunfar.com/why-tamales-are-good-for-the-planet-the-trail-and-you&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on irunfar.com&lt;/a&gt;, and come back here to leave a comment :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glacier Scientist Goes Running</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/dakota/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/dakota/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Excerpt from the full article by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/thatdakotajones/?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dakota Jones&lt;/a&gt; published on  &lt;a href=&#34;https://thatdakotajones.medium.com/a-glacier-scientist-goes-running-e9adc3ede38c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere south and east of Fairbanks, Alaska there’s a little town that has a Russian grocery store. This is not entirely unexpected. For several hundred years beginning in the 17th century, Russian traders and trappers rampaged across the Alaskan landscape like spurned lovers, murdering seals, whales, and indigenous peoples with unbounded enthusiasm, and they made a great deal of money in the process. In time, this colonial regime was replaced by another one, this time from the south. The Americans took over Alaska officially in 1867 and have managed its seals, whales, and indigenous peoples like one might manage a livestock business. But the Russian influence persists in the state. Children can learn Russian in school; there are Russian immigrant communities. And, to serve this niche population, there are various shops stocked with Russian goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside this grocery store, though, hidden between shelves of strange foods with cyrillic labels, the persistent shopper can root out a store of frozen pizzas. And it’s this hoard that has many times served the last-minute needs of a young glaciologist named Sam Herreid, who spent so much time in his office at the University of Alaska, Fairbanks, double-checking batteries, cameras, and fancy thermal sensors for his field trips onto the glacier that he forgot to include what you might call batteries for himself, namely food. Realizing after driving out of the thin suburbs of his hometown into one of the largest wildernesses on Earth that he hadn’t actually packed anything to eat, he was often grateful to skid to a stop in front of the grocery store and emerge shortly thereafter with several frozen pizzas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the rest of this article written by Dakota Jones &lt;a href=&#34;https://thatdakotajones.medium.com/a-glacier-scientist-goes-running-e9adc3ede38c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on Medium&lt;/a&gt;, and come back here to leave a comment :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glaciologist in Chamonix</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/trailrunner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/trailrunner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Published in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trailrunnermag.com/people/environment-people/a-glaciologist-in-chamonix/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Trailrunner Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, online and in print.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a 22-mile round trip run from Chamonix to Le Refuge du Couvercle this September, I found myself with quite a bit of air beneath my feet.  I was scrambling down one of the many ladders that drop down to the Mer de Glace. Over time, more and more ladders have appeared to reach the receding glaciers’ surface, a tactile reminder of a warming climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glaciers are the ubiquitous poster child of climate change, and Chamonix is full of them. Nearly every pioneering study in glaciology took place in the Alps, but it’s other regions on Earth, notably the Himalaya and Andes, where changes will be most directly felt by humans. Indirect effects, like sea-level rise, threaten countless coastal communities where the source of the additional water is from far away locations like Greenland, Antarctica and Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a trail runner and glaciologist, I witness the changing landscape on a regular basis. The Alps offer an acute awareness of these magnificent, and rapidly diminishing relics of a colder past. I hope to retrace my steps up to the Mer De Glace, but, in the meantime, I might take a few fewer flights and eat a few fewer avocados to maybe save myself, and all of us, one more rung on the ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My ultra running history</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/running_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/running_history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than race, I enjoy running un/self-supported trail and urban ultras on my own. They are usually the result of a momentary random fixation on a challenge or destination and the run usually happens within a few days of getting the idea :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This running style is predicated on long, off-trail runs in the Alaska Range that filled the summer months of my 20s and came before I ever thought to buy a GPS watch to track them. Most were done alone, usually alongside fieldwork, but I participated in a few events and races during this time, including: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newsminer.com/features/outdoors/twelve-adventurous-competitors-tackle-100-mile-alaskacross-course/article_932600aa-1658-11e5-ad1c-83467e260409.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AlaskaCross&lt;/a&gt; 100 mile wilderness race in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wm100.endurancenorth.org/2014-results&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;White Mountains 100&lt;/a&gt; (skiing) x2 finishes in 2011 and 2014, &lt;a href=&#34;http://trackleaders.com/iditasport15i.php?name=Sam_Herreid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Iditasport&lt;/a&gt; (225 mile human-powered race on the Iditarod Trail, skiing, 2015, sctatched at mile 51 Yentna Station, only career DNF), the inaugural &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelcreek50.org/results-2015/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Drew&amp;rsquo;s Angel Creek 50 Miler&lt;/a&gt; in 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yukon-news.com/sports/roots-mchale-top-the-field-in-river-trail-marathon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Yukon River Trail Marathon&lt;/a&gt; in Whitehorse Yukon Territory Canada x3 finishes (2010, 2014 and 2015), and 9 consecutive &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adn.com/sports/article/saari-plays-catchup-collect-fifth-equinox-marathon-title/2015/09/20/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Equninox Marathon&lt;/a&gt; finishes from 2007 to 2015, before moving to The UK for graduate school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since leaving Alaska, and buying my first GPS watch, I&amp;rsquo;ve run a steady volume of self-supported trail and urban ultras with a special love for &amp;ldquo;My front door to ___&amp;rdquo; routes with public transportation back home. Here are some of my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tynemouth to Haltwhistle via Hadrian&amp;rsquo;s Wall (87 km), May 2016 (just before getting my first Garmin)
Joshua Tree Traverse (57 km, 1200 m d+), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1174042869&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;December 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Front door (Gateshead) to Seaham (45 km), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1174003177&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;February 2017&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1170251129&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;July 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Front door (Gateshead) to Durham (50 km), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1170251093&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;July 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Unsupported Bob Graham Round attempt (70 km, 5000 m d+) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1752605644&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;August 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Gran Canaria running and climbing holiday (9 days, sum 170 km, 7100 m d+) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2013647528&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;December 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Self-supported run across the Alps (France, Switzerland and Italy; 8 days [2 rest/storm days], 300 km, 15000 m d+), August 2019 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2601994636&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2604388699&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2607609978&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2616081241&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2618167350&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 7&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2621901821&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Day 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The perimeter of Manhattan Island, night running into the new year (52 km), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/2972114410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;December 31, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Run across New Jersey, Atlantic Ocean to Pennsylvania (76 km) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/4032418107&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;September 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Front door (Bradley Beach) to Manhattan (90-100 km), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/4250464257&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;October 2020 Leg 1&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/4250462955&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Leg 2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/4251466916&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Leg 3&lt;/a&gt;; and again &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/6230518566&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;November 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Delaware-Raritan Canal Trail (111 km) &lt;a href=&#34;https://fastestknowntime.com/fkt/sam-herreid-delaware-raritan-canal-trail-nj-2021-04-05&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;April 2021, FKT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Front door (Bradley Beach) to Princeton (73 km) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/6322892945&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;November 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Road PR/PBs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://marathonview.net/marathon-results-of-Sam%20Herreid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2:48&lt;/a&gt; marathon, Zürich Marathon, 2019&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parkrun.org.uk/townmoor/results/athletehistory/?athleteNumber=2811329&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;17:08&lt;/a&gt; 5k, Newcastle upon Tyne Town Moor Parkrun, 2017&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
