<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sam Herreid</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sam Herreid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 All photos and figures by Sam Herreid (profile photo by M. Schlapfer, glacier bike thumbnail by S. Bridwell)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canwell Glacier Research Program</title>
      <link>/project/canwellglacier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/canwellglacier/</guid>
      <description>During my undergraduate at the University of Alaska Fairbanks, I participated in a summer Field Glaciology course. While we focused on traditional bare-ice glaciological methods, I was fixated on how the measurements we were making were not representative of the neighboring ice covered by rocks. When I learned that that debris-covered portions of glaciers were often treated like bare glacier ice in most studies, I wrote a student research proposal to investigate this on my own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debris Cover Tools</title>
      <link>/project/dct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dct/</guid>
      <description>Glaciers are constantly in a state of flux. In addition to glacier evolution, rock debris rafting on the surface, surface streams and supraglacial lakes are all also evolving, likely at independent rates. The glacier surge event shown above is an extreme example of this, but within an unstable climate, all glaciers will undergo dramatic changes over decadal to centennial time-scales. Quantifying this change is the first step in understanding and modeling the greater questions in glaciology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global scale analyses and products</title>
      <link>/project/global/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/global/</guid>
      <description>In order to derive a global debris cover map at an operative quality, the Randolph Glacier Inventory Version 6.0 needed to be corrected and updated. Becasue I was the sole glaciologist to manually correct this dataset, there is now a heightened level of cosistency that has never before been present in a global glacier dataset.
With a high confidence map of glacier area and debris cover, an equilibrium line estimate can be made for glaciers with sufficient debris cover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landslides on glaciers</title>
      <link>/project/landslides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/landslides/</guid>
      <description>Landslides, more technically rock avalanches, are striking features when deposited onto glaciers. Since 2010 I have been both scientifically and personally interested in visiting as many as I can while also keeping an eye on satellite imagery for the next big one&amp;hellip; They are all quite unique, as you will see from some of my favorites shown below.
The Delta Mountains, a sub-range of the Alaska Range. Landslides are shown in red and letters correspond to the locations of the images below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermal imagery in glaciology</title>
      <link>/project/thermal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/thermal/</guid>
      <description>The thumbnail image to this project is of fist to silt-sized clasts on an otherwise bare glacier ice surface. The thumbnail image falls within one or two pixels in the image above which is looking straight down from a helicopter with an image width of several hundred meters. High resolution thermal data holds many answers about debris cover but has received limited attention from glaciologists. Work that is in preparation will detail new methods for acquisition, processing and applications for glaciologists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>