<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction | Sam Herreid</title>
    <link>https://samherreid.io/tag/introduction/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://samherreid.io/tag/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Introduction</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://samherreid.io/media/icon_hu4111fabdab116352ce8a62ad911042e7_28769_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/tag/introduction/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>First blog post of all time!</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to samherreid.io! A new hub for my content spanning a handful of, not always complementary, fixations. My first personal website, samherreid.org, went live in June 2018 as a primarily academic website. It had some footnotes to my other interests, but was built specifically for the eyes of potential employers. I never said ‘‘fuck’’ on samherreid.org. But things are changing&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the domain extension. No one has time to comment on things, those that do occupy a beautiful few percentages of our population. When samherreid.org launched there wasn’t public commenting, but a few people privately messaged me, laughing at my ambitious organization designation. It made some sense to me because it was a well-known extension and I’m not a commercial entity. But now that I am a co-founder of an actual nonprofit organization, I decided to switch my personal website to the trendy .io extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this website still has a comprehensive presentation of my science, I decided to ditch the selective resume format and host all of my creative fields in on one central &amp;ndash; and not social media &amp;ndash; location. Am I still applying for postdocs with a link to this website on my CV? Yes 😅, but I guess I’ve decided to be my whole self here, which means expect inline emojis and jokes about eating Tide Pods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new website has an uncomplicated comments section on all posts, articles and projects and I challenge you to be in the few percent who leave a comment, joke, question or criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script defer src=&#34;https://cdn.commento.io/js/commento.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;commento&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
