<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction | Sam Herreid</title>
    <link>https://samherreid.io/tag/introduction/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://samherreid.io/tag/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Introduction</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://samherreid.io/media/icon_hu4111fabdab116352ce8a62ad911042e7_28769_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/tag/introduction/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>First blog post of all time!</title>
      <link>https://samherreid.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://samherreid.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new samherreid.io, a hub for my content spanning several interests. My first personal webiste, samherreid.org, went live in June 2018 as a primarily academic website that had some footnotes of my other interests in life, but I built and updated the website with potential employers in mind. I never said ‘‘fuck’’ on samherreid.org, for example. But things are changing 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIrst of all the domain. No one has time to comment on things, those that do occupy a beautiful few percentages of our population. When samherreid.org launched there wasn’t public commenting but a few people privately messaged me, laughing at my ambitious organization designation. It made sense to me becasue it was a well known extension and I’m not a commercial entity, but now that I am co-running an actual nonprofit orginization, I decided to switch my personal website to the trendy .io extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the website still has a comprehensive presentation of my science, I decided to ditch the selective resume format and host all of the fields I am creating in on one central, and not social media, location. Am I still applying for postdocs, with this website on my CV? Yes 😅 but I guess I’ve decided to be myself wholly here, which will probably include some fucks, emojis and jokes about eating Tide Pods 😊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new website has an uncomplicated comments section on all posts and I challenge you to be the few percent and leave a comment, joke, question or criticism. Swearing encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
