<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Sam Herreid</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Sam Herreid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 All photos and figures by Sam Herreid (profile photo by M. Schlapfer, glacier bike thumbnail by S. Bridwell)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Denali (6,194 m) so big? Caught inside the tectonic wake of a migrating restraining bend</title>
      <link>/publication/denali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/denali/</guid>
      <description>Topography along strike-slip fault restraining bends is theoretically self-limited by erosion, block translation and the expected abandonment of fault bends. However, Denali (6,194 m) and Foraker (5,304 m) are located within a restraining bend of the dextral Denali Fault system. We reveal the role of bend evolution in mountain building with physical experiments scaled to simulate the Alaska Mount McKinley restraining bend (MMRB). Despite the natural complexity of the MMRB, first-order patterns (of strike-slip separation rates, uplift and lateral bend migration) from the geologic data align with patterns from scaled experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can thermal imagery tell us about glacier melt below rock debris?</title>
      <link>/publication/thermal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/thermal/</guid>
      <description>A 5 post series on my Instagram gives a summary of this paper in accessable language and tells the story about what it took to personally finance it.
[Below] Oblique image of Canwell Glacier from the same helicopter flight used to capture the (straight downward-looking) images above (July 29th, 2016 11:00 AM local Alaska time). Rock debris on the surface of a glacier can dramatically reduce the local melt rate, where the primary factor governing melt reduction is debris layer thickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can thermal imagery tell us about glacier melt below rock debris?</title>
      <link>/publication/thermal_featured/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/thermal_featured/</guid>
      <description>A 5 post series on my Instagram gives a summary of this paper in accessable language and tells the story about what it took to personally finance it.
[Below] Oblique image of Canwell Glacier from the same helicopter flight used to capture the (straight downward-looking) images above (July 29th, 2016 11:00 AM local Alaska time). Rock debris on the surface of a glacier can dramatically reduce the local melt rate, where the primary factor governing melt reduction is debris layer thickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing the Arctic (Book Chapter)</title>
      <link>/publication/arcticocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/arcticocean/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping ice cliffs on debris-covered glaciers using multispectral satellite images</title>
      <link>/publication/marincliffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/marincliffs/</guid>
      <description>Ice cliffs play a key role in the mass balance of debris-covered glaciers, but assessing their importance is limited by a lack of datasets on their distribution and evolution at scales larger than an individual glacier. These datasets are often derived using operator-biased and time-consuming manual delineation approaches, despite the recent emergence of semi-automatic mapping methods. These methods have used elevation or multispectral data, but the varying slope and mixed spectral signal of these dynamic features makes the transferability of these ap-proaches particularly challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of rock debris covering Earth&#39;s glaciers</title>
      <link>/publication/global/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/global/</guid>
      <description>A summary of this paper written in accessable language for the Nature Sustainability Community &amp;ldquo;Behind the Paper&amp;rdquo; series is available here.
Rock debris can accumulate on glacier surfaces and dramatically reduce glacier melt. The structure of a debris cover is unique to each glacier and sensitive to climate. Despite this, debris cover has been omitted from global glacier models and forecasts of their response to a changing climate. Fundamental to resolving these omissions is a global map of debris cover and an estimate of its future spatial evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of rock debris covering Earth&#39;s glaciers</title>
      <link>/publication/global_featured/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/global_featured/</guid>
      <description>A summary of this paper written in accessable language for the Nature Sustainability Community &amp;ldquo;Behind the Paper&amp;rdquo; series is available here.
Rock debris can accumulate on glacier surfaces and dramatically reduce glacier melt. The structure of a debris cover is unique to each glacier and sensitive to climate. Despite this, debris cover has been omitted from global glacier models and forecasts of their response to a changing climate. Fundamental to resolving these omissions is a global map of debris cover and an estimate of its future spatial evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated detection of ice cliffs within supraglacial debris cover</title>
      <link>/publication/icecliffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/icecliffs/</guid>
      <description>Ice cliffs within a supraglacial debris cover have been identified as a source for high ablation relative to the surrounding debris-covered area. Due to their small relative size and steep orientation, ice cliffs are difficult to detect using nadir-looking space borne sensors. The method presented here uses surface slopes calculated from digital elevation model (DEM) data to map ice cliff geometry and produce an ice cliff probability map. Surface slope thresholds, which can be sensitive to geographic location and/or data quality, are selected automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated detection of unstable glacier flow and a spectrum of speedup behavior in the Alaska Range</title>
      <link>/publication/surge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/surge/</guid>
      <description>Surge‐type glaciers are loosely defined as glaciers that experience periodic alterations between slow and fast flow regimes. Glaciers from a variety of mountain ranges around the world have been classified as surge type, yet consensus of what defines a glacier as surge type has not always been met. A common source of dispute is the lack of a succinct and globally applicable delimiter between a surging and nonsurging glacier. The attempt is often a Boolean classification; however, glacier speedup events can vary significantly with respect to event magnitude, duration, and the fraction of the glacier that participates in the speedup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satellite observations show no net change in the percentage of supraglacial debris-covered area in northern Pakistan from 1977 to 2014</title>
      <link>/publication/pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pakistan/</guid>
      <description>Spatial evolution of supraglacial debris cover on mountain glaciers is a largely unmonitored and poorly understood phenomenon that directly affects glacier melt. Supraglacial debris cover for 93 glaciers in the Karakoram, northern Pakistan, was mapped from Landsat imagery acquired in 1977, 1998, 2009 and 2014. Surge-type glaciers occupy 41% of the study area and were considered separately. The time series of debris-covered surface area change shows a mean value of zero or near-zero change for both surging and non-surging glaciers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Derivation and analysis of a complete modern-date glacier inventory for Alaska and northwest Canada</title>
      <link>/publication/akinventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/akinventory/</guid>
      <description>We present a detailed, complete glacier inventory for Alaska and neighboring Canada using multi-sensor satellite data from 2000 to 2011. For each glacier, we derive outlines and 51 variables, including center-line lengths, outline types and debris cover. We find 86 723 km2 of glacier area (27 109 glaciers &amp;gt;0.025 km2), ∼12% of the global glacierized area outside ice sheets. Of this area 12.0% is drained by 39 marine-terminating glaciers (74 km of tidewater margin), and 19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass-balance changes of the debris-covered glaciers in the Langtang Himal, Nepal, from 1974 to 1999</title>
      <link>/publication/langtang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/langtang/</guid>
      <description>Thick debris cover on glaciers can significantly reduce ice melt. However, several studies have suggested that debris-covered glaciers in the Himalaya might have lost mass at a rate similar to debris-free glaciers. We reconstruct elevation and mass changes for the debris-covered glaciers of the upper Langtang valley, Nepalese Himalaya, using a digital elevation model (DEM) from 1974 stereo Hexagon satellite data and the 2000 SRTM (Shuttle Radar Topography Mission) DEM. Uncertainties are high in the accumulation areas, due to data gaps in the SRTM and difficulties with delineation of the glacier borders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Randolph Glacier Inventory: a globally complete inventory of glaciers</title>
      <link>/publication/rgi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/rgi/</guid>
      <description>The Randolph Glacier Inventory (RGI) is a globally complete collection of digital outlines of glaciers, excluding the ice sheets, developed to meet the needs of the Fifth Assessment of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change for estimates of past and future mass balance. The RGI was created with limited resources in a short period. Priority was given to completeness of coverage, but a limited, uniform set of attributes is attached to each of the ~198 000 glaciers in its latest version, 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using surface velocities to calculate ice thickness and bed topography: a case study at Columbia Glacier, Alaska, USA</title>
      <link>/publication/icethickness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/icethickness/</guid>
      <description>Information about glacier volume and ice thickness distribution is essential for many glaciological applications, but direct measurements of ice thickness can be difficult and costly. We present a new method that calculates ice thickness via an estimate of ice flux. We solve the familiar continuity equation between adjacent flowlines, which decreases the computational time required compared to a solution on the whole grid. We test the method on Columbia Glacier, a large tidewater glacier in Alaska, USA, and compare calculated and measured ice thicknesses, with favorable results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier trends and response to climate in Denali National Park and Preserve</title>
      <link>/publication/dnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dnp/</guid>
      <description>Glaciers cover approximately one-sixth of Denali National Park and Preserve in Alaska. They are not only enjoyed by visitors for their scenic and recreational values but are also an important driver of Denali&amp;rsquo;s diverse ecosystems by defining the hydrologic regime, generating landscape-scale braided river systems, and shaping the landforms of the Alaska Range. Scientists from the National Park Service and University of Alaska-Fairbanks have been researching glacier dynamics and monitoring glacier trends for more than 20 years using glacier outlining from satellite imagery, index mass balance measurements, longitudinal elevation profiles, repeat photography, analysis of regional gravity changes, and other localized research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>